rough: adj. 崎岖不平的
Lesson 39. Nothing to worry about. The rough across the plane soon became so bad that we tried
第39课。没什么可担心的。飞机上的粗糙很快变得如此糟糕，我们尝试了
to get Bruce to drive back to the village we had come from. Even though the road was littered
要让布鲁斯开车回到我们来的村庄。即使道路乱扔
boulder: n.   大石块, pit: v.   使得坑坑洼洼, perturb: v.   使不安
with boulders and pitted with holes. Bruce was not in the least perturbed. Lansing at his map,
带有巨石，并带有孔。布鲁斯没有扰动。在他的地图上兰斯
he informed us that the next village was a mere 20 miles away. It was not that Bruce always
他告诉我们，下一个村庄只有20英里外。不是布鲁斯总是
underestimate: v.   低估
underestimated difficulties. He simply had no sense of danger at all. No matter what the
低估的困难。他根本没有危险的感觉。不管是什么
conditions were, he believed that a car should be driven as fast as it could possibly go.
条件是，他认为应尽可能快地驾驶汽车。
boulder: n.   大石块, swerve: v.   急转变, scoop: v.   挖出
As we bumped over EH Dusty Track, we swerved to avoid large boulders. The wheels scooped
当我们撞到EH Dusty轨道时，我们转弯以避免大巨石。车轮sc起
hammer: v.   （用锤）击打，锤打, ominously: adv. 有预兆的，不祥的
up stones which hammered ominously under the car. We felt sure that sooner or later a stone
上的石头在汽车下不祥地锤击。我们确定迟早是一块石头
rip: v.   划破，撕，扯, petrol: n.   汽油
would rip a hole in our petrol tank or damage the engine. Because of this, we kept looking back,
会在我们的汽油箱中撕裂一个孔或损坏发动机。因此，我们一直回头，
petrol: n.   汽油
wondering if we were leaving a trail of oil and petrol behind us. What a relief it was when
想知道我们是否要留下石油和汽油的痕迹。当
boulder: n.   大石块, stretch: n.   一大片（平地或水）, obstacle: n.   障碍
the boulders suddenly disappeared, giving way to a stretch of plane where the only obstacles were
巨石突然消失了，让位于唯一障碍的飞机上
clump: n.   丛，簇, fissure: n.   （石，地的）深缝
clumps of bushes. But there was worse to come. Just ahead of us there was a huge fissure.
一团灌木丛。但是情况更糟。就在我们前面，有一个巨大的裂痕。
fissure: n.   （石，地的）深缝, renew: v.   重复, pleading: n.   恳求
In response to renewed pleadings, Bruce stopped, though we all got out to examine the fissure.
为了回应新的诉状，布鲁斯停止了，尽管我们都出去检查了裂缝。
fissure: n.   （石，地的）深缝
He remained in the car. We informed him that the fissure extended for 50 years and was tow
他留在车里。我们告诉他，裂缝延长了50年，被拖了
gear: n.   汽车排档
feet wide and four feet deep. Even this had no effect. Bruce went into a low gear and drove at
英尺宽，深四英尺。即使这也没有效果。布鲁斯走进低矮的装备，开车去
crack: n.   缝隙, zigzag: n.  “之”字形
a terrifying speed. Keeping the front wheels astride the crack as he followed its zigzag course.
一个恐怖的速度。在他沿着曲折的路线沿裂缝的过程中，保持前轮横穿裂缝。
Before we had time to worry about what might happen, we were back on the plane again.
在我们有时间担心可能发生的事情之前，我们又回到了飞机上。
Bruce consulted the map once more and told us that the village was now only 15 miles away.
布鲁斯再次咨询了地图，并告诉我们该村庄现在只有15英里。
obstacle: n.   障碍, shallow: adj. 浅的
Our next obstacle was a shallow pool of water about half a mile across. Bruce charged at it,
我们的下一个障碍是大约半英里处的浅水池。布鲁斯对此充电，
dashboard: n.   （汽车上的）仪表盘
but in the middle, the car came to a grinding half. A yellow light on the dashboard
但是在中间，汽车磨了一半。仪表板上的黄灯
flashed angrily and Bruce cheerfully announced that there was no oil in the engine.
愤怒地闪烁着，布鲁斯高兴地宣布发动机中没有石油。